[
    {
        "question": "Ðæs <em>(biscop)</em> #### swearta stan  — The bishop’s black stone",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopes",
        "explanation":"Here 'biscop' is in the singular genitive so it takes the 'es' ending",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "biscopa",
                "explanation": "While 'biscop' is in the genitive, it is the singular 'biscopes'. Biscopa' is the genitive plural"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Se <em>(þegen)</em> #### ond þa biscops fram Readingum — The thane and the bishops from Reading",
        "correctAnswer": "þegen",
        "explanation":"Here 'þegen' is the subject so it takes the nominative singular case",        
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs cyninges <em>(þegen)</em> #### ferde to þæm tune  — The king’s thanes went to the town",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnas|þegenas",
        "explanation":"Here 'þegen' is the subject and in the plural, so it takes the 'as' ending of the plural nominative",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "þegen",
                "explanation": "While not apparant in the Old English, þegen is clearly plural in the modern English trans, and so takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða <em>(cyning)</em> #### ond þa biscopas on Æscesdune — The kings and the bishops in Ashdown",
        "correctAnswer": "cyningas",
        "explanation":"Here 'cyning' is the subject and plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "cyning",
                "explanation": "'Cyning' is the singular form of the word while the above word is plural. This means the correct answer is 'cyningas'. If you're not sure whether a word is plural or singular, check the demonstrative pronoun."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Eall þara <em>(biscop)</em> #### preostas ferde to þæm halige stede mid him — All the bishops’ priests went to the holy place with them",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopa",
        "explanation":"Here 'biscop' is in the possessive plural, since there are multiple priests belong to multiple bishops, so it takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": [
            {
                "incorrectAnswer": "biscopas",
                "explanation": "Biscopas is the nominative or accusative plural. The genitive plural ends in 'a', so the correct answer is 'biscopa'."
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In Þæs (<i>cyning</i>) #### tune   —  In the town of the king",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninges",
        "explanation":"Here 'cyning' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða þegnas þara <em>(cyning)</em> #### Ælfred and Æþelred — The thane's of the Kings' Alfred and Ethelred",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninga",
        "explanation":"Here 'cyning' is in the possessive plural so it takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<i>biscop</i>) #### fram þæm tune —  The bishop from the town",
        "correctAnswer": "biscop",
        "explanation":"Here 'biscop' is the subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða Þegnas ond se (<i>cyning</i>) #### —  The thanes and the king",
        "correctAnswer": "cyning",
        "explanation":"Here 'cyning' is subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Fram þæs (<i>þegen</i>) #### tune   —  From the thane’s town",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnes|þegenes",
        "explanation":"Here 'þegen' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se cyning ond þa (<i>biscop</i>) #### —  The king and the bishops",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopas",
        "explanation":"Here 'biscop' is part of the subject and plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðæs (<i>þegen</i>) #### menn  —  The thane’s men",
        "correctAnswer": "þegnes|þegenes",
        "explanation":"Here 'þegen' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Menn fram Þara (<i>þegen</i>) #### tunum — Men from the towns of the thanes",
        "correctAnswer": "þegna|þegena",
        "explanation":"Here 'þegen' is in the possessive plural as the men are from towns belonging to the thanes, so it takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða <em>(stan)</em> #### fram þæs þegnes tune — The stone from the thane’s town",
        "correctAnswer": "stanas",
        "explanation":"Here 'stan' is subject and is plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Se (<i>stan</i>) #### ond se þegen   —  The stone and the thane",
        "correctAnswer": "stan",
        "explanation":"Here 'stan' is subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",        
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ðara <em>(wicing)</em> #### cyning wolde þæt þa Deniscan ricsoden ofer Englalande - The king of the vikings would that the Danes ruled over England",
        "correctAnswer": "wicinga",
        "explanation":"Here 'wicing' is in the possessive plural as the subject is the king of many vikings, so 'wicing' takes the 'a' ending of the genitive plural",        
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða bearn þæs <em>(cyning)</em> #### beoþ wis and eaþmod - The children of the king are wise and humble",
        "correctAnswer": "cyninges",
        "explanation":"Here 'cyning' is in the possessive singular so it takes the 'es' ending of the genitive singular",        
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Ða <em>(biscop)</em> #### geaf þone stan to þæm þegne — The bishops gave the stone to the thane",
        "correctAnswer": "biscopas",
        "explanation":"Here 'biscop' is the subject and it is plural so it takes the 'as' ending of the nominative plural",        
        "commonMistakes": []
    },
    {
        "question": "Giet wæs se <em>(cyning)</em> #### Ælfred geong - Still, the king Alfred was young",
        "correctAnswer": "cyning",
        "explanation":"Here 'cyning' is the subject and in the singular so it takes no ending, as per the nominative singular",
        "commonMistakes": []
    }
]



